Heiner Andrés Solano Arguedas

+50664040376 Heredia heiner.andres@outlook.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with 5 years working in development, implementation and maintenance of technological solutions. With knowledge of programming languages, databases and operating systems. Demonstrated ability to solve complex problems, optimize processes and collaborate in multidisciplinary teams. Focused on innovation and continuous improvement, with communication and leadership skills to coordinate teams.

Stacks:

- ✓ Windows, C# Web, Desktop, Apis, WCF, Azure.
- ✓ <u>Web</u>, Angular, NodeJS, React, Django.
- ✓ Mobile, Java, Kotlin.
- ✓ <u>Data bases</u>, Sql, Oracle, Postgresql.
- ✓ Analytics and data science, Python.

Individual projects

Systems Engineer February 2023 - Present

- 1. Portfolio.
 - React (React Router, Components and Hooks).
 - CSS, responsive design.
 - CI/CD: Version control with Git.
 - CI/CD: Azure App Service deploy.

Web site (May take 2 3 minuts loading the content)

- 2. Amazon page
 - React (React Router, Redux, Components, Hooks, Api integration, Google authentication).
 - CSS, responsive design.
 - Node is (Api creation, database docs and guerys)
 - CI/CD: Version control with Git.
 - CI/CD: Azure App Service deploy.
 - Functionality: LogIn, products view, products stock, card management (add, delete or change the number of products, calculate subtotal.

Web site (May take 2 3 minuts loading the content)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Novacomp February 2022 – November 2022

IT company specialized in software development, outsourcing and technology consulting, present in more than 23 countries Novacomp provides consulting services to help businesses with their digital transformation.

Software Engineer

- Collaborate with clients, project managers and stakeholders to understand the business and technical specifications.
- Work closely with other developers, designers, testers using version control tools and agile methodologies like
- Write clean, efficient and well-documented code using programming languages.
- Test the software to identify bugs and fix them to ensure the proper functionality.
- Participate in teammates code review, promote best practices and share knowledge across the team.
- Stay update with new tools, frameworks and industry trends to bring innovative solutions.

Technologies: C#, Windows Forms, WCF, SQLServer, Git, CI/CD pipelines, Azure, TFS.

Multinational technology company, specialized in IT solutions. With presence in 14 countries, Babel focuses on emerging technologies, including generative AI, cybersecurity, hyperautomation, data analytics, and cloud solutions.

Software Engineer

- Understand the project analyzing client and stakeholder requirements to define clear software objectives.
- Participate in agile workflows such as dailys, sprint planning and retrospectives to align development efforts.
- Develop robust and scalable applications following best coding practices and design patterns.
- Debug and troubleshoot errors in the codebase, analyzing causes and implementing effective solutions.
- Review teammates code to identify potential issues, suggest improvements and share knowledge.
- Research with new frameworks, languages and methodologies to bring innovations to the projects.

Technologies: C#, MVC, Rest Api, SQLServer, Git, CI/CD pipelines, Azure, TFS.

Optimized Data Solutions

August 2016 – January 2018

Outsourcing company that specializes in provide high-quality IT and data services to international clients.

Software Engineer

- Define what the software has to do identifying user ideas and aligning them.
- Translate software designs and specifications into functional code that meets project requirements.
- Ensure software behaves as expected by executing test cases, resolving defects and validate user requirements.
- Use version control systems and communication tools to coordinate tasks and share knowledge.
- Maintain a clean and efficient codebase, review processes and collaborative discussions.
- Learn about modern technologies that align with project goals and improve team productivity.

Technologies: C#, MVC, WCF, SQL, TFS.

<u>Seidor</u> March 2015 – Juny 2016

Global technology consulting firm, partner company in businesses improving efficiency and customer experiences, specializes in provide Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP).

Software Engineer

WM technical consulting in an SAP implementation, create a soap to communicate the ERP and the android studio application. The app reads barcodes for the movement of products sending information to de ERP and showing the transportation orders information.

Technologies: Python, Android Studio, Java, Postgresql.

Python (library to host the program in a Windows process, library to communicate with SAP, library to create a SOAP, installations and configurations).

Android Studio (research to read barcodes, communication with the SOAP, permissions, activities, intents, etc)

EDUCATION

- Universidad Nacional, Heredia, Costa Rica. Information Systems Engineering (2018).
- Invenio-Sykes, San José, Costa Rica. English for employability Programa (2020).

CURSES

- UNA, Python Programming for Data Science
- ♣ UNA, Apps Development with Android Studio
- Udemy, Angular, Javascript Jquery, NodeJS
- Udemy, React cero to expert (Hooks y MERN)
- Udemy, IOS & Swift, The complete development Bootcamp
- Udemy, Git curse
- Hacker Mentor Academy, Cibersecurity.